GUILLAUME DE ROO

1086 Fulton Street • Apt 1 • San Francisco, CA 94117 • USA guillaume.de.roo@gmail.com • +1 415 802 8349

SUMMARY

Consultant with international leadership experience, and recent focus on technology industry and pricing. Strong track record of applying problem framing and analytical skills to develop strategic and operational solutions in various industries (telecommunications, retail and energy).

Enthusiasm for machine learning and self-driving cars, with 20h/week spent on classes and projects since 2016.

EXPERIENCE

THE BOSTON CONSULTING GROUP

2011 - PRESENT

PRINCIPAL (2016 -), **PROJECT LEADER** (2013-16), **CONSULTANT** (2012-13), **ASSOCIATE** (2011-12) FRANCE, BRAZIL, USA Driving teams of up to 5 consultants on more than 25 projects

Market strategy

- Designed roadmaps for key cities, including sales target, marketing message and 4G investment, for South American mobile network operator cities covered by 4G increased from 45 to 1200 in 2 years
- Assessed market potential (focus groups, survey), and identified partners along value chain for non-store retail company entering South America company concluded on higher potential in Asia and pivoted
- Defined portfolio of promising bio technologies for South American pulp and paper manufacturer company took \$20M stake and signed partnership with target in most promising technology
- Assessed partnership portfolio of South American loyalty program, and identified expansion targets company secured partnerships with several targets, including largest supermarket chain with \$13B revenue

Pricing & Sales

- Product Manager of pricing applications on BCG's software platform 4 apps developed since Q4 2016
- Built pricing model for North American software company with \$300M revenue, switching from onpremise to cloud – established new metrics, guidelines, pricing desk, and secured first deals with +30% revenue
- Investigated dealership sales policies of North American truck manufacturer losing \$50M / year to exchange rate variation identified hedging strategy as issue, and suggested new policy reducing loss by 90%
- Created peer group analysis tool to identify cross-sell targets at European commercial bank tool used to increase communication between commercials, with 30% of client opportunities confirmed

Organization transformation

- Conducted operational cost optimization program at South American gas and oil leader personal supervision of creation and monitoring of opportunities worth \$400M (20% reduction on \$2B/year cost branch)
- Implemented turnaround plan for construction of 1.6 GW nuclear reactor in Europe cleaning up of schedule, economics and risks led to announcement of 2 year delay and 20% cost increase

DIRECT ÉNERGIE

2009 - 10

PROIECT EXECUTIVE TO THE COO

PARIS, FRANCE

- Developed economic models and legal briefs for nuclear tariffs, demand-response and capacity markets
- Improved consumption estimation algorithm for billing reduced standard error by 50%
- Defined and set-up Key Performance Indicators throughout organization

MIT CENTER FOR ENERGY & ENVIRONMENTAL POLICY RESEARCH

2007 – 09

RESEARCH ASSISTANT OF EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR

Cambridge, MA

Published several articles on electricity markets and nuclear power economics

EDUCATION

University of California, Berkeley

2016 – Present Berkeley, CA

Pursing M. Information & Data Science

2007 - 09

M.Sc. Technology & Policy • M.Sc. Nuclear Science & Engineering

MASSACHUSETTS INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

CAMBRIDGE, MA

ÉCOLE POLYTECHNIQUE

2004 - 07

B.Sc. • M.Sc. Applied Mathematics and Economics (entry rank: 3rd, Mathematics cohort) Palaiseau, France

CERTIFICATIONS & LANGUAGES

UDACITY:Self Driving Car (2017 - Present)COMPUTER SKILLS:Microsoft Office (daily)COURSERA:Machine Learning (2016)Python, R (proficient)STANFORD:Statistical Learning (2015)Matlab, SQL (updatable)

PROJECTS: gderoo.github.io TensorFlow, Hive, Spark (learning)

GREEN CARD HOLDER FRENCH: Native FORTUGUESE: Fluent FRENCH NATIONALITY ENGLISH: Fluent GERMAN: Elementary

OTHER

Outside interests: Travel, Music, Horse-riding, Baking